Seeley Family Papers, 1742-1892 Ms 29
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Seeley Family Papers, 1742-1892
Ms 29
Fairfield Museum and History Center
0.5 Linear feet (1 Box, 60 items)
Papers from the Seeley family of Fairfield, CT and nearby Weston and Easton. Consists mostly of deeds, writs, and probate papers. Account books and Yale College material are also in the collection.
Seeley family
Box Oversize Manuscript Box 1
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
The first Seeley's settled in the Fairfield area in the late 16oo's. The papers in this collection belonged to family members who lived in Fairfield and surrounding towns including Easton and Weston. They include farmers, a school teacher, a military officer, a postmaster and politicians. More genealogical information can be found in History and Genealogy of the Families of Old Fairfield Volume II, Part III by Donald Lines Jacobus, Fairfield, CT, 1930.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of one box and three oversize items. Folder A in Box I contains deeds, Folder B holds Yale College material and Folder C has legal and financial papers, certificates and correspondence. An account book of the Weston Turnpike can be found in Folder D. Oversize Item A is an account book, Item B an estate map and Item C a postmaster's commission.
Custodial History note
Some of the collection was donated by Lila Seeley Osborne Hall on 9/28/1977. The earliest deed in the collection was donated by David Hey [L2007.3].
Separated Materials note
Oversize Item B and C are located in the Oversize Manuscript Box 1.
Seeley, Aaron, 1778?-1864; Seeley, Charles S., fl. 1877-1884; Seeley, Mallett; Yale College (1718-1887) .; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Easton(Conn.); Probate records--Connecticut--Fairfield; Teachers--Certification--Connecticut.; Weston Turnpike Company; Weston(Conn.); Writs--Connecticut.
- Deeds, 1742-1886; Folder A; 22 items
  Other Finding Aids note
  A detailed list of items is available in the Box.
- Charles S. Seeley Yale College material, 1877-1884; Folder B; 17 items
  - Entrance and final exams, 1877-1884; 10 items
  - Commencement exercises, catalogues, etc., 7 items
- Legal and financial papers, certificates and correspondence, Folder C; 20 items
  - Writ-John Silliman Andrews vs. Nathan Seeley, 1782
  - Writ-Stephen Guyer vs. Nathan Seeley, 1785
  - Aaron Seeley probate papers, 1846, n.d.; 2 items
  - Ebenezer Seeley probate papers, n.d.
  - Nathan Seeley probate papers, 1789
  - Samuel J. Seeley probate papers, n.d.
  - Samuel Jackson probate papers, n.d.
  - Bills to Aaron Seeley, 1841, n.d.; 2 items
  - Frank S. Seeley teacher's certificate for Fairfield, 1891-1892
  - Mallett Seeley Postmaster certificate, 1835
  - Mallett Seeley military certificates, 1825, 1829; 2 items
  - Correspondence, 6 items
- Account book of E. S. Seeley, Treasurer of Weston Turnpike, 1860-1882; Folder D
- Loose papers from E. S. Seeley account book, 1866-1887; Folder E
- Oversize Item A: Aaron Seeley's farm and store account book, 1800-1860
- Oversize Item B: Map of Ezra Seeley's estate, 1827
- Oversize Item C: Mallett Seeley's Postmaster Commission, 1837